<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>summary on lubieniebieski by adam nowak</title><link>https://lubieniebieski.pl/categories/summary/</link><description>Recent content in summary on lubieniebieski by adam nowak</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 22:17:52 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lubieniebieski.pl/categories/summary/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>February Summary</title><link>https://lubieniebieski.pl/posts/2023/03/february-summary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 22:17:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://lubieniebieski.pl/posts/2023/03/february-summary/</guid><description>Another month has passed and it&amp;rsquo;s time to summarize it.
We had a little holiday in Krak贸w with the family. Hard to call it a regeneration but still, it was nice to spend some time together. We had a nice whether, including -10掳C during the day. Highlights: Wieliczka, Wawel, Muzeum Iluzji, Paac Krzysztofory, Wesoa Cafe, AleKlocki. During the Krak贸w visit, I had a chance to experience the BMW 3 series for the first time in the 370+HP version and explore the city with my guide D.</description><content>&lt;p>Another month has passed and it&amp;rsquo;s time to summarize it.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>We had a little holiday in Krak贸w with the family. Hard to call it a regeneration but still, it was nice to spend some time together. We had a nice whether, including -10掳C during the day. Highlights: Wieliczka, Wawel, &lt;a href="https://krakil.pl/">Muzeum Iluzji&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://muzeumkrakowa.pl/oddzialy/palac-krzysztofory">Paac Krzysztofory&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://wesolacafe.pl/">Wesoa Cafe&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.aleklocki.com/">AleKlocki&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>During the Krak贸w visit, I had a chance to experience the BMW 3 series for the first time in the 370+HP version and explore the city with my guide D. - thanks a lot for the opportunity! It was great! The most important insight for me was that I don&amp;rsquo;t really need a full M version of the car, the one I tested is more than enough!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I spent a lot of time digging through BMW configurator, it seems that cars still make an impression on me.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>February was not impressive in terms of bike trips, just 3 of them. I hope that my issues with the tires are gone and I won&amp;rsquo;t have to spend most of the ride pumping them up.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>February marks my 4th month in a row when I closed all the activity rings on my Apple Watch!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>At work things were good but INTENSIVE, the highlight was a workshop we had in a bigger group in Pozna! First of all we closed some important topic, but there was also a lot of fun and a lot of learning! I also started in a new role &amp;ndash; exciting things ahead of us!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I had my first experience as a host with Disruption Talks format, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/events/howsaascantransformthehospitali7034870321421725696">it was fun&lt;/a>!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.flexispot.com/">FlexiSpot&lt;/a> surprised me when I reached out to them and they agreed to send me a new desk top for free (I had a small issue with the previous one).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Something triggered me to improve my backup game. I decided to leverage the power of my Synology and backup all the photos from all the phones at home to Synology (even though I use the big iCloud package). Just in case. Apart from that, I did some changes to running Docker containers on NAS and I&amp;rsquo;m using it more and more for things other than just a file storage.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I&amp;rsquo;m glad that my home is running almost entirely on Apple devices, just a few things left for migration. Not that I don&amp;rsquo;t like other brands, but it&amp;rsquo;s easier to have everything in one ecosystem.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Health is good!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I felt urge to learn CSS from scratch, hopefully I will find some time for it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I wrote 5 posts on my blog! That&amp;rsquo;s more than in 3 last years combined!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="few-random-links">Few random links&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1794680/Vampire_Survivors/">https://store.steampowered.com/app/1794680/Vampire_Survivors/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma">https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://logseq.com/">https://logseq.com/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://dokku.com/">https://dokku.com/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@flavourtrip">https://www.youtube.com/@flavourtrip&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M4aPeeI64CA">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M4aPeeI64CA&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://letterboxd.com/">https://letterboxd.com/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="posts">Posts&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://lubieniebieski.pl/cyk/007/">Cyk007: One night in Krak贸w, Krak贸w, 2023&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://lubieniebieski.pl/posts/2023/02/uses-page-is-up/">Uses Page Is Up&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://lubieniebieski.pl/posts/2023/02/exploring-www/">Exploring WWW&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://lubieniebieski.pl/posts/2023/02/playing-with-webmentions/">Playing with Webmentions&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://lubieniebieski.pl/january-was-nice/">January was NICE&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>February, &lt;strong>thank you! &lt;/strong>&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>