<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RSS on lubieniebieski by adam nowak</title><link>https://lubieniebieski.pl/tags/rss/</link><description>Recent content in RSS on lubieniebieski by adam nowak</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 21:10:38 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lubieniebieski.pl/tags/rss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exploring WWW</title><link>https://lubieniebieski.pl/posts/2023/02/exploring-www/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 21:10:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://lubieniebieski.pl/posts/2023/02/exploring-www/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently realized that my habits for interacting with World Wide Web changed over time. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I spend my time, consume the content and communicate in the internet.
In general RSS &amp;ndash; oh boy, I&amp;rsquo;ve never left the RSS boat, even after Google Reader was shutdown years ago. Right now I use it to browse a very diverse (also random) set of feeds to broaden my perspectives and follow the topics I&amp;rsquo;m interested about &amp;ndash; without the comments/likes hustle.</description><content>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently realized that my habits for interacting with World Wide Web changed over time. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I spend my time, consume the content and communicate in the internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="in-general">In general&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>RSS&lt;/strong> &amp;ndash; oh boy, I&amp;rsquo;ve never left the RSS boat, even after Google Reader was shutdown years ago. Right now I use it to browse a very diverse (also random) set of feeds to broaden my perspectives and follow the topics I&amp;rsquo;m interested about &amp;ndash; &lt;strong>without the comments/likes hustle&lt;/strong>.
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The last part is crucial for me &amp;ndash; RSS are about the content, not everything around it. That&amp;rsquo;s actually how I like to browse web.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Newsletters&lt;/strong> &amp;ndash; when I was a very active developer back in a day, I felt that being on the edge with news about programming languages, new libraries, etc. was a must. After a while, I realized that receiving TOP-10 links from a given topic once a week is enough. I still believe that&amp;rsquo;s the case and that&amp;rsquo;s why I like reading newsletters:) One caveat &amp;ndash; RSS feed is still better when executed nicely.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mastodon&lt;/strong> &amp;ndash; new player in the block, I covered it my another &lt;a href="https://lubieniebieski.pl/where-am-i-2023/">post&lt;/a>. Currently, it serves as my tiny social network and inspiration for browsing other people&amp;rsquo;s blogs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Random pages on the internet&lt;/strong> &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;m combining Mastodon toots with subscribing to people&amp;rsquo;s feeds. Most of the time, people are not that active on blogs, write 10 pages a year or something like that. But that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I like &amp;ndash; exploring this random stuff, finding great content (and collecting another ideas to explore). I still don&amp;rsquo;t want to leave &amp;ldquo;the bubble&amp;rdquo; but at the same time feel comfortable with content &amp;ldquo;on the edge&amp;rdquo;.
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This approach exposes me to a quite varied set of topics which I probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t find otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Facebook Groups&lt;/strong> &amp;ndash; there&amp;rsquo;s really good content in FB groups! I avoid things that are &amp;ldquo;general&amp;rdquo;, like city-based groups, etc., I focus on specialized groups of people who talk and exchange ideas about a narrow topic, e.g. woodworking, car detailing or cycling. I don&amp;rsquo;t like the interaction process, but you can get a lot by the extended context of comments in some discussions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Messenger/Signal/WhatsApp/iMessage&lt;/strong> &amp;ndash; depending on the group of people I&amp;rsquo;m interacting with, instant messaging app changes and I can&amp;rsquo;t really tell which one is my platform of choice. The biggest problem I have is that the most people are on the platforms I&amp;rsquo;d like to utilize the least 🙃&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>All these activities have enabled me to stay connected and up-to-date with the ever-growing world of the web. I enjoy the freedom of browsing, exploring and learning from the world wide web, and I am constantly experimenting and adapting to the best ways to do so. Even without realizing that I do experiment:)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="work">Work&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Slack&lt;/strong> &amp;ndash; most of my work happens there. Mentions, tasks, daily job. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to say it&amp;rsquo;s my main working tool - actually it is and my work happens through Slack. I do fun and serious stuff there, but there&amp;rsquo;s always too much going on.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>E-mail&lt;/strong> &amp;ndash; not used that much anymore, forwarding from time to time, intros, contacting with people outside of the company&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>LinkedIn&lt;/strong> &amp;ndash; networking is important part of my role and LinkedIn gives me the best visibility and chance to understand what&amp;rsquo;s going on &amp;ldquo;professionally&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>After writing this, I came to a conclusion that this is just a general outline of how do I interact with the Web, without concrete details. That&amp;rsquo;s totally OK &amp;ndash; if you would like me to expand some of the channels a bit, let me know!&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>