<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>webmentions on lubieniebieski by adam nowak</title><link>https://lubieniebieski.pl/tags/webmentions/</link><description>Recent content in webmentions on lubieniebieski by adam nowak</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 22:23:48 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lubieniebieski.pl/tags/webmentions/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Playing with Webmentions</title><link>https://lubieniebieski.pl/posts/2023/02/playing-with-webmentions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 22:23:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://lubieniebieski.pl/posts/2023/02/playing-with-webmentions/</guid><description>With so many site visitors and reactions on Mastodon (LOL), I decided to try out webmentions.
I&amp;rsquo;m using webmention.io to receive and send webmentions. I&amp;rsquo;m also using bridgy to combine that with reactions/replies from Mastodon.
The first time I&amp;rsquo;ve heard about webmentions, was when I stumbled upon Robb Knight&amp;rsquo;s article. Robb&amp;rsquo;s website is beautiful and encouraged me to read more about webmentions and actually implement them on my website.
What are webmentions?</description><content>&lt;p>With so many site visitors and reactions on Mastodon (LOL), I decided to try out webmentions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;a href="https://webmention.io">webmention.io&lt;/a> to receive and send webmentions. I&amp;rsquo;m also using &lt;a href="https://brid.gy/">bridgy&lt;/a> to combine that with reactions/replies from Mastodon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first time I&amp;rsquo;ve heard about webmentions, was when I stumbled upon &lt;a href="https://rknight.me/adding-webmentions-to-your-site/">Robb Knight&amp;rsquo;s article&lt;/a>. Robb&amp;rsquo;s website is beautiful and encouraged me to read more about webmentions and actually implement them on my website.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-are-webmentions">What are webmentions?&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Webmentions are a form of web communication that allow one website to notify another about mentions or links to its content.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>They are a modern alternative to traditional trackback and pingback systems and provide a way for one website to notify another that it has linked to its content.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Webmentions are a key part of the &lt;a href="https://indieweb.org/">IndieWeb&lt;/a> movement, which aims to give individuals more control over their online identity and data.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In practice, webmentions work by sending a request from the linking website to the target website with information about the link, such as the URL of the linking page and the URL of the linked page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The receiving website can then use this information to display a notification or summary of the mention on its site.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Webmentions offer a more open and decentralized way of communicating between websites and can help to foster a more connected and engaged web.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="future-plans-for-webmentions-on-lubieniebieskipl">Future plans for webmentions on lubieniebieski.pl&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Of course, the first paragraph was a bit of a joke, with 2 reactions on Mastodon, there&amp;rsquo;s not a lot of incentive to spend a lot of time on webmentions here. However, I believe that eventually, I&amp;rsquo;d would be great to connect the content here with other places on the web, to spark discussions, to get more feedback, to cross-link content when it makes sense.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>For now, there&amp;rsquo;s not even a div for webmentions on the site, but the &amp;ldquo;backend&amp;rdquo; is already working.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-implement-webmentions">How to implement webmentions?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Have a look at following sites, I think they are a great starting point and were enough for me to get webmentions working here:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://rknight.me/adding-webmentions-to-your-site/">All in one with a beautiful example&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/PlaidWeb/webmention.js">Showing webmentions on site (JS plugin)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.jayeless.net/2021/02/integrating-webmentions-into-hugo.html">Starting with webmentions in Hugo&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://webmention.io">webmention.io&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://brid.gy/">bridgy&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item></channel></rss>