<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>site on lubieniebieski by adam nowak</title><link>https://lubieniebieski.pl/categories/site/</link><description>Recent content in site on lubieniebieski by adam nowak</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 22:23:48 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lubieniebieski.pl/categories/site/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Playing with Webmentions</title><link>https://lubieniebieski.pl/posts/2023/02/playing-with-webmentions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 22:23:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://lubieniebieski.pl/posts/2023/02/playing-with-webmentions/</guid><description>With so many site visitors and reactions on Mastodon (LOL), I decided to try out webmentions.
I&amp;rsquo;m using webmention.io to receive and send webmentions. I&amp;rsquo;m also using bridgy to combine that with reactions/replies from Mastodon.
The first time I&amp;rsquo;ve heard about webmentions, was when I stumbled upon Robb Knight&amp;rsquo;s article. Robb&amp;rsquo;s website is beautiful and encouraged me to read more about webmentions and actually implement them on my website.
What are webmentions?</description><content>&lt;p>With so many site visitors and reactions on Mastodon (LOL), I decided to try out webmentions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;a href="https://webmention.io">webmention.io&lt;/a> to receive and send webmentions. I&amp;rsquo;m also using &lt;a href="https://brid.gy/">bridgy&lt;/a> to combine that with reactions/replies from Mastodon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first time I&amp;rsquo;ve heard about webmentions, was when I stumbled upon &lt;a href="https://rknight.me/adding-webmentions-to-your-site/">Robb Knight&amp;rsquo;s article&lt;/a>. Robb&amp;rsquo;s website is beautiful and encouraged me to read more about webmentions and actually implement them on my website.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-are-webmentions">What are webmentions?&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Webmentions are a form of web communication that allow one website to notify another about mentions or links to its content.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>They are a modern alternative to traditional trackback and pingback systems and provide a way for one website to notify another that it has linked to its content.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Webmentions are a key part of the &lt;a href="https://indieweb.org/">IndieWeb&lt;/a> movement, which aims to give individuals more control over their online identity and data.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In practice, webmentions work by sending a request from the linking website to the target website with information about the link, such as the URL of the linking page and the URL of the linked page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The receiving website can then use this information to display a notification or summary of the mention on its site.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Webmentions offer a more open and decentralized way of communicating between websites and can help to foster a more connected and engaged web.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="future-plans-for-webmentions-on-lubieniebieskipl">Future plans for webmentions on lubieniebieski.pl&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Of course, the first paragraph was a bit of a joke, with 2 reactions on Mastodon, there&amp;rsquo;s not a lot of incentive to spend a lot of time on webmentions here. However, I believe that eventually, I&amp;rsquo;d would be great to connect the content here with other places on the web, to spark discussions, to get more feedback, to cross-link content when it makes sense.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>For now, there&amp;rsquo;s not even a div for webmentions on the site, but the &amp;ldquo;backend&amp;rdquo; is already working.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-implement-webmentions">How to implement webmentions?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Have a look at following sites, I think they are a great starting point and were enough for me to get webmentions working here:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://rknight.me/adding-webmentions-to-your-site/">All in one with a beautiful example&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/PlaidWeb/webmention.js">Showing webmentions on site (JS plugin)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.jayeless.net/2021/02/integrating-webmentions-into-hugo.html">Starting with webmentions in Hugo&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://webmention.io">webmention.io&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://brid.gy/">bridgy&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>Hello Hugo!</title><link>https://lubieniebieski.pl/hello-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 10:36:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://lubieniebieski.pl/hello-hugo/</guid><description>So&amp;hellip; Last night I had this idea of changing one more thing in my setup and that was to move my site from Wordpress to Hugo. For a few last days I had been thinking about it and I was really curious how it would work out. I had a few things in mind that I wanted to achieve with this change:
migrate away from my hosting provider and reduce costs have a static site that I can host anywhere (Github Pages included) have a site that is easy to maintain and update have a way to write posts in Markdown have a feeling of doing something new and exciting have a site that is fast and lightweight being able to write posts in my favorite editor (currently VS Code, as my Vim muscle memory faded away a bit) do something &amp;ldquo;hackish&amp;rdquo; and fun Here we are!</description><content>&lt;p>So&amp;hellip; Last night I had this idea of changing one more thing in my setup and that was to move my site from Wordpress to Hugo.
For a few last days I had been thinking about it and I was really curious how it would work out. I had a few things in mind that I wanted to achieve with this change:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>migrate away from my hosting provider and reduce costs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>have a static site that I can host anywhere (Github Pages included)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>have a site that is easy to maintain and update&lt;/li>
&lt;li>have a way to write posts in Markdown&lt;/li>
&lt;li>have a feeling of doing something new and exciting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>have a site that is fast and lightweight&lt;/li>
&lt;li>being able to write posts in my favorite editor (currently VS Code, as my Vim muscle memory faded away a bit)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>do something &amp;ldquo;hackish&amp;rdquo; and fun&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Here we are! I&amp;rsquo;m happy with the result! There are a few things that I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce, like light/dark theme switcher or a better way of handling images, but I&amp;rsquo;ll get to that later.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Where am I 2023?</title><link>https://lubieniebieski.pl/where-am-i-2023/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 16:28:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lubieniebieski.pl/where-am-i-2023/</guid><description>After the events in Twitter back in 2022, I decided to rethink a bit my visibility there and other social media. Somehow, I ended up with a pretty old-school conclusion.
I&amp;rsquo;m giving this blog/site another go. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect to post multiple times a day, but a few entries a year would be a nice improvement comparing to the last few years&amp;hellip;
Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m exploring a few things:
Mastodon lubieniebieski@social.lol as a Twitter alternative and re-entry to interactions in the webz if you&amp;rsquo;re out there &amp;mdash; let me know!</description><content>&lt;p>After the events in Twitter back in 2022, I decided to rethink a bit my visibility there and other social media. Somehow, I ended up with a pretty old-school conclusion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m giving this blog/site another go. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect to post multiple times a day, but a few entries a year would be a nice improvement comparing to the last few years&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m exploring a few things:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Mastodon &lt;a href="https://social.lol/@lubieniebieski">lubieniebieski@social.lol&lt;/a> as a Twitter alternative and re-entry to interactions in the webz if you&amp;rsquo;re out there &amp;mdash; let me know!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2FA improvements with &lt;a href="https://www.yubico.com/">YubiKey&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Loving RSS more than ever (thanks &lt;a href="https://reederapp.com/" title="Reeder 4 for Mac and iOS">Reeder&lt;/a>!)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Changing my e-mail setup a bit &amp;mdash; I decided to buy a domain and run it on &lt;a href="https://ref.fm/u29262816" title="Referral link for Fastmail - get 10% off your first year!">Fastmail&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>My plan is to write about these topics a bit more in upcoming weeks.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Cheers!&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Hello world! (WordPress this time!)</title><link>https://lubieniebieski.pl/hello-world-wp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 21:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lubieniebieski.pl/hello-world-wp/</guid><description>Hello 👋!
I&amp;rsquo;m experimenting with my site right now, stay tuned for the updates!</description><content>&lt;p>Hello 👋!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m experimenting with my site right now, stay tuned for the updates!&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>