<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>omg.lol on lubieniebieski by adam nowak</title><link>https://lubieniebieski.pl/tags/omg.lol/</link><description>Recent content in omg.lol on lubieniebieski by adam nowak</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 22:19:03 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lubieniebieski.pl/tags/omg.lol/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>January was NICE</title><link>https://lubieniebieski.pl/january-was-nice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 22:19:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://lubieniebieski.pl/january-was-nice/</guid><description>Here are some of things that were with me in January. A few @adam tools and a few observations I have made recently.
Tools I realized that I like people and things that are NICE and welcoming. Places where we say &amp;ldquo;hello&amp;rdquo; to each other, where we are polite and where we are not afraid to ask for help or simply we can share what we think without being judged.</description><content>&lt;p>Here are some of things that were with me in January. A few &lt;a href="https://social.lol/@adam">@adam&lt;/a> tools and a few observations I have made recently.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="tools">Tools&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I realized that I like people and things that are NICE and welcoming. Places where we say &amp;ldquo;hello&amp;rdquo; to each other, where we are polite and where we are not afraid to ask for help or simply we can share what we think without being judged.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="arc-browser2---a-browser-for-the-modern-web">&lt;a href="https://arcbrowser.com/">Arc browser&lt;/a> - a browser for the modern web&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After a few years of browsing Internet and jumping on the Chrome boat right from the beginning, I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect that there&amp;rsquo;s going to be a browser that&amp;rsquo;s going to make me switch. But Arc browser did it. It&amp;rsquo;s fast, it&amp;rsquo;s simple, it&amp;rsquo;s beautiful and it&amp;rsquo;s NICE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I love the sidebar and a &amp;ldquo;magic&amp;rdquo; feel of interacting with favorites and tabs. But most of all, I like how the entire thing is designed. It&amp;rsquo;s not just a browser, it&amp;rsquo;s a whole experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The way new releases are presented and also the way the team is communicating with the community is just amazing. Look at an example here: Arc team is presenting a release without major updates, but with a lot of small improvements. It&amp;rsquo;s just 💙.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QVIMuNz1IRY" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Even though I&amp;rsquo;m usually the picky person, liking when everything is aligned, polished, pixel-perfect and beautiful &amp;mdash; I enjoy the &amp;ldquo;chaos&amp;rdquo; of what the Arc team is sharing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Their screens are messy, there are a lot of thinks on the desktop, record quality is not 8K, some footage is done via iPhone directly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But it&amp;rsquo;s all NICE.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="omglol3--a-social-network-">&lt;a href="https://omg.lol">omg.lol&lt;/a>- a social network (?)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After a recommendation in &lt;a href="https://yeswas.pl/">YesWas Podcast&lt;/a>, I was curious what this &lt;code>omg.lol&lt;/code> thing is. I thought it was a Mastodon server, but it&amp;rsquo;s more than that. For a small yearly fee, you get a subdomain &lt;code>YOURNAME.omg.lol&lt;/code> + a lot of extras including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>web profile / simple homepage&lt;/li>
&lt;li>URL shortener&lt;/li>
&lt;li>custom DNS management&lt;/li>
&lt;li>weblog&lt;/li>
&lt;li>statuslog&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>/now&lt;/code> page (&lt;a href="https://sive.rs/nowff">link to the &amp;ldquo;movement&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>mastodon server&lt;/li>
&lt;li>email forwarding&lt;/li>
&lt;li>and many more&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>And what&amp;rsquo;s interesting, every feature is accessible via API. When you interact with the page you see a lot of things like:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>We hope you&amp;rsquo;re having a great day.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Need more help? Contact us at any time.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Colors are friendly, everything is extremely polished - links work, many feature are available, there&amp;rsquo;s a status page, &lt;a href="https://omglol.news/">news&lt;/a>, crazy domains. And when I got to the Mastodon instance, I was warmly greeted by &lt;a href="https://social.lol/@adam">@adam&lt;/a> who runs the entire gig. NICE!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BTW: there&amp;rsquo;s a possibility to use all the cool features under your own domain, so if you feel like there&amp;rsquo;s something cooler than omg.lol domain, you can do it!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="mastodon8">&lt;a href="https://joinmastodon.org/">Mastodon&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve started my journey on mastodon early this year, you can see my activity by following &lt;a href="https://social.lol/@lubieniebieski">lubieniebieski@social.lol&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what Mastodon is, you can take a look here:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://mastodon-poradnik.pl/">Poradnik&lt;/a> for my Polish friends by &lt;a href="https://masto.ai/@lukem">@lukem@masto.ai&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For everyone else speaking English &lt;a href="http://guidetomastodon.com/">http://guidetomastodon.com&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://elekk.xyz/@noelle">@Noelle@elekk.xyz&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>So far, I like it and try to post something from time to time. I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;a href="https://tapbots.com/ivory/">Ivory&lt;/a> on my iPhone and I&amp;rsquo;m still looking for a decent client for the desktop. The web version of the client is OK, but I&amp;rsquo;m missing the ability to resume the timeline when I finished last time, not to jump right away to the newest posts.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hugo15-static-site-engine">&lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo&lt;/a> static site engine&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve already shared my hello-world &lt;a href="https://lubieniebieski.pl/hello-hugo/">post&lt;/a> regarding Hugo, but I forgot to mention that this entire thing is written in Go (Hu - Go&amp;hellip; !:D) which I recently explored as my language of choice for hacking after work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s fast, it&amp;rsquo;s NICE:) And you read this post — which I consider the biggest achievement of my migration from Wordpress to Hugo.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>